live
like say welcome brothers and sisters to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the ten
commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel
and God spake all these words saying I
am the Lord thy God which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt out of the
house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquities of the fathers upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that take of his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it
holy. Six days shall thou labor and do
all thy work. But the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God, and that
thou shall not do any work. Thou nor
that son, nor thy daughter, that man's
servant, nor that maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor that stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the seat, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefor the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill,
thou shalt not commit adultery, thou
shall not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shall not cover thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not cover thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. We
read Exodus 20 1-17. And may the Lord
have a blessing to the reading of his
words. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long- scripture questions as well as the
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep your questions to a
two scripture maximum. Let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Julius.
Good evening everybody. Brother Dre.
Good evening. Brother Jerome, grace and
peace. Brother Tanzel, good evening
everybody. Sister Deborah, good evening.
And we have Sister Casey with us as well
as the guest caller. And I'm brother
Cornell. Sister Deborah, what is our
first question of the evening? Uh, yes,
there are several uh held over questions
that will be answered first before
getting into tonight's Q&A.
Asher question asks, "Are Jesus parables
considered prophecy or just stories?"
I've heard someone teach that the eye of
the needle in Matthew
19:4 is a small gate used to enter
Jerusalem. It's just a parable.
All right. So, they want to know about
the Jesus parables. Are they considered
prophecy or just stories? I'm going to
ask the guest caller to shed some light.
Why don't you read Matthews 19 and 24
first? Matthew 19 and
24.
Right. And again, I say unto you, it is
easier for a camel to go through the eye
of a needle than for a rich man to enter
into the kingdom of God.
Now it's and when this is a a
parable whether there is a small gate in
Jerusalem or not the Bible don't say but
the Lord use parables and parables are
what you call
metaphors. That's when you use one thing
to define something else or similar. Now
we give you an example.
Let's go into Mark the 4th
chapter and we're going to read 1
through5 then we're going to
skip. All right. Mark
and he be and he began again to teach by
the seaside and there was gather unto
him a great multitude so that he enter
into a ship and sat in the sea and the
whole multitude was by the sea on the
land. And he taught them many things by
parables, and said unto them in his
doctrine, hearken, behold, there went
out a ser to sow. And it came to pass as
he sold, some fell by the
wayside, and the fowls of the air came
and devoured it
up. That was in verse four.
45. and some fell on stony ground where
it had not much earth and immediately it
spranged up because it had no depth of
earth.
What verse is that? That was in a fire.
Okay. Now, it look like we are planting
seed, don't it? Right. Mhm.
Somebody's planting planting a crop or
something and and certain things happen
to the seed like some of not deep
enough. the flowers come eat them and
some is is uh uh uh didn't take sprout
and they died the heat. This have
nothing to do with sewing. Now let's
let's let's skip down to verse 11 and
find out what is really talking about.
Verse 11-13.
And he said unto them, unto you it is
given to know the mystery of the kingdom
of God, but unto them that are without.
All these things are done in
parables, that seeing they may see and
not perceive, and hearing they may hear
and not understand, lest at any time
they should be converted, and their sins
should be forgiven them. And he said
unto them, "Know ye not this parable?
And how then will ye know all parables?"
The serth the word and these are they by
the wayside where the word is sown. But
when they have heard
now what he s have no seed in it had
nothing to do with plant the crop. He
said the swer swed the word. Okay.
And uh uh and and what happened? The so
and so the word. Go ahead. And these are
they by the wayside where the word is
sown. But when they have heard Satan
come up immediately and taketh away the
word that was sown in their hearts. So,
so you get and you go and you teach show
somebody the word of God and uh uh all
of a sudden somebody come up and they
want to get involved and and dispute
what you saying and take the word away
from them. But go ahead.
And these are they likewise, which are
sown on stony ground, whose when they
have heard the word, immediately
received it with gladness, and have no
root in
themselves, and so endure but for a
little but for a time. Afterwards, when
affliction or persecution arises for the
word's sake, immediately they are
offended.
They and so know that someone hear the
word and they happy to hear it. But as
soon as this word cause a little drama
in their life, they offend it and they
want to get away from it. So this is the
way a metaphor work. The Lord used the
sewing of seed like you're planting a
crop to let you know that all seeds
don't take root and some do. So it is
with the word of God. So the one that
swed the word is the Lord. And it fell
on good bad grounds and some people uh
uh uh you know uh uh did had allowed
somebody to take it away from them and
some of them they heard it and they
liked it. But as soon as they had a
little drama, they walked away from it
and some fell on good ground and it took
root and then it grew into fruit and
they was able to teach it to somebody
else. So that's what the parables are.
They're metaphors. Lord tell you about
one thing that that's pointing towards
something else. As far as the needle's
eyes concerned, the Lord said whosoever
will come and there's nobody that have a
situation especially riches that's going
to keep them from getting
salvation. But if you kept reading that
would have told you to God all things
are possible. Right?
So that's what parables are a
metaphor. That's all I have to say. All
right. Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question. Moving on. Tomorrow
Williams asks, "Where is it written
about that the sun will have the earth
so hot during the great tribulation?"
the sun having the earth so hot. Brother
Jerome, what you say?
Uh, I got two places I want to uh go to.
Uh, Revelation 16 and then second Peter.
Let's do the Revelation 16 first.
Revelation 16 and read verse
89. When you get it, go ahead and read.
And the fourth angel poured out his bow
upon the sun. And power was given unto
him to scorch men with
fire, and men were scorched with great
heat, and blaspheing the name of God,
which had power over these plagues. And
they repented not to give him glory.
Yeah. And so that verse talked about how
during this is during the great
tribulation when the trumpets uh are
being blown and he said
uh when when the trumpet is blown of
course a vial is going to be poured out
and when that vial is poured out he say
it's going to be uh cause the sun to
scorch
men and okay and burn
men. Uh let's go to second Peter chapter
3 and read verse
10. Second Peter chapter 3 verse 10.
But the day of the Lord will come as a
thief in the night into which the
heavens shall pass away with a great
noise and the elements shall melt with
fervent heat. the earth also and the
works that are therein shall be burnt
up. Yeah, there's another place. We're
not gonna go there, but there's another
place where he said, you know, the Lord
ain't going to do ain't going to destroy
this earth by water like he did in the
past. He's going to destroy with fire
when he return. Okay, it's still going
to buy it though. He just gonna beat
this earth up. And one of the ways he
gonna do it is with fire. That's all I
got.
All right, thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question. Next, next question.
Malik Shakur says in Genesis 3
verse14, if the serpent is a man, what
does upon thy belly shall thou go and
dust shall thou eat all the days of thy
life mean?
All
right. Starts off with if the serpent is
a man, shed some light, brother Julius.
The serpent is not a man. The serpent is
Satan, the dragon. Let's go, Tanzil to
Genesis chapter 3 and read verse one.
Genesis 3 and 1. When you get it, Tazia,
go ahead and read. Now the serpent was
more sus sustive than any beast of the
field which the Lord God had made. And
he said unto the woman, "Yeah, have God
said you should not eat of every tree of
the garden?" So now this right here is
none other than Satan the dragon. Skip
down. So because he deceived the woman,
she took the doctrine, his doctrine back
to the man. They both were deceived. But
this is Satan the devil. It's a title.
So now let's go. Serpent is a title.
Read verse 14. Look at this. Look at his
judgment. Go ahead and read it. And the
Lord God said unto the serpent, "Because
thou hast done this, thou are cursed
above all cattle, and above every beast
of the field. Upon thy belly shalt thou
go, and thus shalt thou eat all the days
of thy life." So now he said, "You're
cursed above." So this is a judgment
that's poured down upon none other than
Satan, the devil. He said, "Upon thy
belly shalt thou go." Which represents
uh a spiritual condemnation. He's
spiritually condemned. Okay. So now he
said, "Upon thy belly shall thou go." So
the Lord fixed him so that he cannot pop
up and deceive you. But to show you that
a serpent is not a man, let's go to
Revelation the 12th chapter and get his
title and see what he really
is. Revelation chapter 12.
And we going to read pick it up at verse
three. We're going to read verses 3 and
verse
4. Notice what what he's called here.
His title here is called Revelation 3 uh
12 3 and 4. Go ahead and read. And there
appeared another wonder in heaven.
Uhhuh. And behold, a great red
dragon having seven heads and 10 horns
and seven crowns upon his head. So this
is Satan the devil in the form of the
head of the European Union. Okay. Now,
but this is the a fallen angel. He's
called a great red dragon here. But read
verse four. Look who fell with him. And
his tail drew the third part of the
stars of heaven and did cast them to the
earth. And the dragon stood before the
woman which was ready to be delivered
for to devour her child as soon as it
was born. Now let's read skip down to
verse seven and get and look what he did
again. Go ahead. And there was war in
heaven. Michael and his angels fought
against the dragon. And the dragon
fought and his angels. So now these are
these are angels, sisters and brothers.
These are angels. Michael is the captain
of the Lord's host. Satan the dragon or
Satan the devil is the serpent. He's
also called the dragon. Now let's get
all of his titles at verse nine. Go
ahead. And the great dragon were cast
out. That old serpent called the devil
and Satan which deceiveth the whole
world. He was cast out into the earth
and his angels were cast out with him.
So this is not a man. This is a fallen
angels that went against God and all the
angels that listened to him fell with
him. So now let's look at what he did in
Jude. Go to the little book right before
Revelation. Jude and read verse
6 because remember upon thy belly shalt
thou go. So he's condemned and he the
power was taken away from him to appear
before people. Go ahead. And the angels
which kept not their first estate but
left their own habitation he have
reserved an everlasting chains under
darkness until the judgment of the great
day. So now these fallen angels is the
same ones are the third part of the
stars of heaven which are fallen angels.
That's just metaphoric for the fallen
angels that follow after Satan. Onethird
of them and the book says they he has
reserved an everlasting chains of under
darkness. Dark chains represent you
being restricted. So he fix so you can
he cannot just pop pop up before you. So
now chains represents restriction.
Darkness represents something that you
cannot see. So the Lord fixed him in
Genesis the third chapter. His
punishment was you are not going to be
able to appear before people anymore.
You can still maneuver uh you can still
uh maneuver through their mind. They
still exist. They are still here. They
are hidden up under chains of darkness.
So they cannot just pop up on you and
appear. They cannot appear, but yet they
exist. If you read Ephesians the 6th
chapter, it would tell you that we fight
not against flesh and blood, but against
spiritual wickedness in high places
against the rulers of the darkness of
this world. You cannot see these evil
angels operating per se, but yet they're
operating through people through the
manipulation of their minds. They're
persuading their minds. So that's what
Genesis 3 and 14 mean. the devil upon
thy belly shalt thou go. I'mma fix you
so you cannot appear before people. You
can't deceive them uh in person like
like that anymore. They have to be
persuaded through their minds. I hope
that helped.
And uh brother Julie and that dust shalt
thou eat all the days of thy life. It
just mean you are condemned to the you
are condemned to the earth. You can't
the book tell you that their place was
found no more in heaven.
The earth is their
prison. All right. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Next one. Melon Natural Journey
says, "My family member said a curse
word to me against me and my children
and then text me to call him is
important. I know we're supposed to
forgive, but it hurt. What should I do?
But it hurt, brother Dre. What you say?
Yeah. Um, I think you should tell them
how you feel. But let's go to Matthew
the 18th chapter and see what the book
say you should
do. Matthew 18 and we're going to read
verse 15. Matthew 18 and verse 15. And
we're going to skip. Go ahead when you
get it, Tanzia. Moreover, if thy brother
shall trespass against thee, go and tell
him his faults between thee and him
alone. If he shall hear thee, thou hast
gain thy brother. So you got to tell him
what you feeling, you know, and maybe
it's an opportunity that he want to
apologize to you for what he said, you
know. Now skip down to verse 21 and read
21 and 22. Go ahead. Then came Peter to
him and said,"Lord, how often shall my
brother sin against me?" And I forgive
him till seven times. And Jesus said
unto him, "I say not unto thee until
seven times, but until 70 times seven."
Yeah. So that's a high calling to
forgive somebody, you know, but maybe he
is seeking something against me.
to uh Galatians
Galatians
and we gonna pick it up at verse one.
Galatians 6 and we going to just read
verse one. When you get that, go ahead,
brother.
Brethren, if a man be overtaken in a
fault, ye which are spiritual, restore
such a one in the spirit of meekness,
considering thyself, lest thou also be
tempted. Yeah. So you let him know how
you feel about him speaking to you in
that way. But at the same time, you
always looking to restore. Let's go to
James 5. Now we going to read verses 19
and 20. And that'll be it. James 5, 19,
and 20. Go ahead when you get it,
brother. Brethren, if any of you do heir
from the truth and one convert him, let
him know that he which convertth the
sinner from the error of his way shall
save a soul from death and shall hide a
multitude of sins. So again, you know,
if if you offended by something that he
said to you, I think you should tell him
and maybe you may be able to restore
that
relationship. And if he's texting you to
call him, maybe he feels some guilt. I
hope it works out for you. That's all I
got. Right.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question. as we
move on to our next question. Next
question. Cool. C cool blue asks, "Is it
wrong to not be wanting to talk to
others in your environment because they
don't try to keep none of God's words
like the 10 and etc. I don't mind saying
hi and being nice, but that's it."
Well, um saying hi and being nice,
that's a good thing to do. But as far as
socializing, that is strictly your
choice. You know, I have um I have
friends I've been knowing for many years
and I may watch the game with them or
play some cards or something to that
effect and the word of God don't even
come up. They're not keeping the 10
either. And I tried to bring that up,
but I lost that battle. So, um, as far
as socializing with them, uh, that's
strictly your choice. But here's the one
thing that you should always be armed
with. Let's go to that. First Peter 3.
First Peter 3 because sometime people
that don't keep it today might later on
come into some desire to keep it, you
know. So, I've had some friends ask me
about the word that we never talked
before. And so this is what you have to
always have on you in that first Peter 3
and read one verse for me brother. Read
that verse
15. But sanctify the Lord God in your
heart. And be ready always to give an
answer to every man that ask of you a
reason of the hope that is in you with
meekness and fear. Yeah. So always keep
God sanctified in your heart. do know
some of them people you choose not to
socialize with might ask you about your
God and you should be prepared to give
them an answer and to let them know
about his goodness and his greatness and
you know so that that might be the
opening door for someone that you have
chosen not to socialize with because
they're not keeping the 10 and if they
being extremely outrageous with breaking
the law of God then hey you have to be
careful of the company that you keep
even when it comes to
that. So that's all I
got and I hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next next
one. Johnny O asks, "Is it wrong for an
unmarried man to desire to be married?"
Is there something wrong with an
unmarried man desiring to be married?
That's a very popular question cuz
sometimes you got sisters that's not
married. has desiring to be married
also. But I think that um you should be
specific, you know, in your prayer.
Let's go to uh Philippians the 4th
chapter. Philippians
4 and we just go read a few scriptures
because you ask about a man versus a
woman. But this also fits the other side
for a woman that might be also looking
for a
husband. Philippians 4. And let's pick
up verse six and
seven. Go ahead.
Be careful for nothing, but in
everything by prayer and supplication
with thanksgiving, that your requests be
made known unto God. So let let God know
that you looking for a wife or you would
like to have a wife or that you would
like to have a husband. Verse seven. And
the peace of God which passes of all
understanding shall keep your hearts and
minds through Christ Jesus. Yes. And so
also during that time while you're
waiting, you should polish yourself up.
If you're a brother, polish yourself up
on what is required to be a good husband
for the marriage. And a wife should be
doing the same thing. If she looking for
a husband, she should be getting out of
the book the words that it take to be a
good wife also. It's a lot less headache
when you got somebody who served the
same God that you serve, which is what I
prayed for. That was 25 years ago. And I
am blessed even to this day because God
delivered for me. But let's go into uh
Proverbs 19. Proverbs the 19th
chapter. When you get to Proverbs 19, we
going to read one
verse and then we going to go to
Proverbs 8. Turn back to 18. Proverbs 19
and verse
14. Go ahead, brother.
House and riches are the inheritance of
fathers and a prudent wife is from the
Lord. Oh, a prudent wife. So, why not
put that in your prayer that you would
like to have a prudent wife, a wife that
is wise and insightful and hey, even
serving the God of Abraham, Isaac, and
Jacob. And the same thing for the
husband or the wife. Now let's turn back
to Proverbs 18 and 22. Proverbs 18 and
22. Because the Lord say that hey that a
proven wife is from him. Why not ask the
Lord to send you a wife and don't be so
quick to pick on your own?
Proverbs 18 and read that one verse 22.
Go ahead. Who so findth a wife findeth a
good thing and obtainth favor of the
Lord. Yes. That's why it's good to have
a a good wife because the Lord said that
hey, who so findth a wife findeth a good
thing and obtain a favor of the Lord.
Same for the sisters. But let's turn
over to Ephesians the fifth chapter and
this will be it. Ephesians 5. Go ahead,
guest caller. Go ahead. Read the
question. The question
was again,
is it wrong? Is it wrong for is it man
to uh desire uh to be married?
No, it's not.
That's the end of it.
All right, we'll leave it there as we
move on to our next question. Uh Brit
Brett has two questions. Uh her first
one is
uh what gate will the people who are not
Israelites go through and revelations
21:12 is given. And the second question
is can you help me with understanding
how to fast?
All right. Revelation 21 and 12. What
gates will the people who are not
Israelites go through? Let's go to
Revelation 21 and 12. And the guest
caller take it from there.
Read it.
And had a great and it had a wall great
and high. They had 12 gates and at the
gates 12 angels and names written
thereon which are the names of the 12
tribes of the children of Israel.
Now the Bible don't
say uh what gate. It only say that they
shall enter into the
city. Read Revelation 21
uh uh uh verses 21- 24.
read uh Revelations 21.
Uhhuh.
And from verse 21 to 24.
Okay. And the 12 gates were 12
pearls. Every several gate was of one
pearl, and the streets of the city was
pure gold, as it were transparent glass.
And I saw no temple therein. For the
Lord God Almighty and the Lamb are the
temple of it. And his city had no need
of the sun, neither of the moon to shine
in it. For the glory of God did lighten
it, and the Lamb is the light thereof.
And the nations of them which are saved
shall walk in the light of it. And the
kings of the earth do bring their glory
and honor into it.
So now it don't say what gate. All they
said that they going to go into it. So I
suppose one gate is just as good as
another right now. The second part is
you want to get understanding on how to
fast. Very
simple. Don't eat or drink anything for
whatever time that you say that you was
going to be fasting. Then if you're
going to fast for 3 days, then you don't
eat no food and you don't drink no
water. You don't put nothing in your
mouth.
That's a fast.
Don't have to say. All right. Hope that
answered your question as we move on
with the time check to our next one.
Yes, the time is 8:03. I Chuck Woo asks,
"How do I explain to my friend who is a
7day Adventist the difference between
their church and Israel of God?"
All right. Seven day adventist.
and the Israel of God. Brother Julius,
what you say about that? First thing I
would ask him, what is the origin of
7day Adventist? Come out of Millerites,
come out of Millerite movement, gentile
doctrine, which
essentially all break when you break it
all the way down, it is a
derivative of the doctrines of the
Catholic Church. Once you break it down
all the way to the lowest and you have
to show the what the Israel of God
teach. So seventh day of vengeance they
acknowledge this Sabbath day but the
doctrines and stuff that they keep is so
much different. Now the Israel of God
let me show you what we are. We are the
original priest of God. We are the
original
Christians. Let's go to
um Acts chapter 11.
Tenzil, we teach salvation for all
people, but we teach also that
salvation, you got to go through Israel,
right? Acts 11 and pick it up at verse
22. Because what they got come out of
Rome. Let's look at what we got come out
of. When you get it, go ahead. Then tidy
of these things came unto the ears of
the church which was in Jerusalem. The
church where? In Jerusalem. The church
that started in Jerusalem really started
in the wilderness under the hand of
Moses. But go ahead and read. And they
sent forth Barnabas that he should go as
far as Antioch. Skip down to verse 25
and 26. Go ahead. Then departed Barnabas
to Tarsus for to seek Saul which who was
whose name was chained to Paul. Go
ahead. And when he had found him, he
brought him unto Antioch. And it came to
pass that a whole year they assembled
themselves with the church and taught
much people. And the disciples were
called Christians first in Antioch. And
what is the duty of
Christians original Christians to go
into all the world and preach the gospel
to every creature they didn't? So they
they have to get it from us and not us
to them. Let's go to Psalm 147 and show
you that. Psalm 147 and show you that.
Psalm 147:10. We going to read verses 19
to 20 because what they got is another
doctrine that come out of Rome. When you
get it, Psalm 147 and 19. What what the
book say? He showed his word unto Jacob
and his statutes and his judgment unto
Israel. Uhhuh. He have not dealt so with
any nation. Uhhuh. And as for his
judgment, they have not known them.
Praise ye the Lord. So he showed
everything to Israel. That's the Old
Testament. Let's go to the New
Testament. My last place. Let's go to
Romans the 9th
chapter. Romans chapter nine. This is
the difference between the seven day
adventures, which is a gentile doctrine,
and what we teach at the Israel of God,
right? Which are the true Israelites,
the true Christians.
Romans nine. Pick it up verse. We going
1 to5. Read quick. I say the truth in
Christ. I lie not. My conscience also
bear me witness in the Holy Ghost that I
have great heaviness and continual
sorrow in my heart. For I could wish
that myself were cursed from Christ for
my brethren, my kinsmen according to the
flesh. See, they think that they got
pictures of Paul as a gentile. Paul was
black because all Israel is black and he
is the original Christian and the
apostle to the Gentiles which the
Millerites uh are. Go ahead. Who are
Israelites to to whom pertainth the
adoption? The adoption
and the adoption and the glory and the
covenant and the giving of the law. Yes.
And the service of God because we are
the priest. Go ahead. and the promises.
Go ahead. One more. Whose are the
fathers and of whom as concerning the
flesh Christ came who is over all God
bless forever. Amen. So Jesus was an
Israelite of the tribe of Judah, the
original Christians. So that is the
difference. That's what you tell you
show whoever it is you're talking to
through scripture that Israel is the
priest of God and the whole world got to
come uh to Israel because Jesus told you
with the woman at the well salvation is
of the Jews. That's all I got.
31 and two
guest caller.
I can throw in one thing. The difference
in the seventh day advent, the major
difference in the seventh day advent and
the Israel of God is that they teach
going to heaven. Yes. They said the
Lord's going we and we teach that the
kingdom is going to be on earth.
Major difference. Thank
you. All right. I hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Moving on. Ran 64
asks, "Will people see Christ sitting on
his throne in the clouds for five months
due to the wrath of God coming down on
earth?"
People see Christ sitting on the throne
in the clouds for five months. Guess
caller.
Yeah. Let's go into
Revelations the uh uh 6th
chapter and we're going to read from
12-1
17. Go ahead and read it. And happy hill
when he had opened the sixth seal, and
lo, there was a great earthquake, and
the sun became black as sackcloth of
hair, and the moon became his blood. And
the stars of heaven failed unto the
earth, even as a fig tree cast of her
untimely figs, when she is shaken of a
mighty
wind. And the heavens departed as a
scroll when it is rolled together. And
every mountain and island were moved out
of their places.
And the kings of of the earth, and the
great men, and the rich men, and the
chief captains, and the mighty men, and
every bond man, and every free man hid
themselves in the dens, and in the rocks
of the mountains. And they said to the
mountains and rocks, "Fall on us, and
hide us from the face of him that siteth
on the throne, and from the wrath of the
Lamb. For the great day of his wrath is
come and who shall be able to stand.
Now when the heaven ruled back like a
scroll, the sun went black, moon red,
stars fall, and the heaven rule back
like a stroll stroll, everybody could
see him. That's why they start calling
from the mountains and the rocks to fall
on him. Right? So now he start pouring
out his wrath upon him. And we just
going to and uh uh and one of the thing
is he's going to let uh the western
European nations which is a beast that
uh uh uh that come out of Bama's pit
assault Eastern Europe. So let's go into
Revelation the 9th chapter and we're
going to read verses 1-5.
Revelation 9. Amen.
And the fifth angel sounded, and I saw a
star fall from heaven unto the earth,
and to him was given the keys of the
bottomless pit pit. And he opened the
bottomless pit, and there arose a smoke
out of the pit, as a smoke of a great
furnace, and the sun and the air were
darkened by reason of the smoke of the
pit. And they came out of the smoke
locust upon the earth, and upon them was
given power as the scorpions of the
earth have power. And it was commanded
them that they should not hurt the grass
on the earth, neither any green thing,
neither any tree, but only those men
which have not the seal of God in their
forehead. And to them it was given that
they should not kill them, but that they
should be tormented five months. And
their torment was as the torment of a
scorpion when it is strike when he
strike ofth man.
So in the meantime the heavens was still
rolled back and Jesus and everybody was
still looking at him and this is just
one place where we know that he going to
allow people to use chemical or joint
warfare and to punish people for five
months. So yeah, he was everybody could
see him during that whole five months.
Probably longer, but we because he ever
is not going to close back up, but we
use five months because we can read it.
That's all I have to say about that.
All right. Well, I hope that answered
your question. As we move on to our next
question, I'd like to open this one to
the panel. Sister D. Yes. I'm answer.
Yes. All right. Uh All right. Shirley
Brown says, "Isn't celebrating birthday
self idolatry?"
Finish it.
That's it.
What you got add on here?
It's nothing. It's just some more
questions that's added on. That's not
that question.
Well, if it was a dog, then it would
have been written in the book.
You're going to commandments that tell
you not to make any images anybody of
anything did in heaven and earth. Right.
Right.
So now and not to bow down and worship
them, didn't
it? So now did we see birthdays do not
have birthdays because of the doctrine
and the commandments?
Nope. In fact, see anybody anywhere is
written in the Bible where you should
you shouldn't have birthdays? Nope.
So that mean if you think that then you
add known you you're doing what the Lord
told you not to do in Revelation.
Anybody add on to the word this plagues
going to be plag this book going to be
uh added to them. And anybody take away
from it then they salvation is going to
be removed. So it's not in the Bible. So
how you going to call it self adultery,
idolatry? Revelation 2 20th chapter said
when the white throne judges over he
saying the books was open and another
book was open which is the book of life
and everyone was judged out of the
things which are written in the books
that's not written in the right.
That's the end of it.
Right. We hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next
question. Uh, next question. Manny Payne
says, "I uh, where I live, the closest
camp or Israel or God is at least 150
miles
away. I study on this Sabbath with IoG
from YouTube. Is this the same as having
convocation? A convocation during the
Sabbath studies and during all of the
feasts of the Lord our God.
Yes, call.
No, it's not the same because the Lord
said you supposed to have a holy
convocation. However, if you are not
able to get there because of means uh uh
uh for reason that you cannot help,
then we uh we will uh uh uh read
something. But before we read that
though, we want to go into
Leviticus 23rd
chapter and read verse three and see
what it says.
Six days shall work be done. But but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of rest and
holy convocation. You shall do no work
therein. It is a Sabbath of rest in all
your
dwelling. So he said have a holy
convocation. So that is not the same.
However, if you can't make it, then
there is some provision for you to be
there in the spirit. Go into Colossians
the 2 chapter and read verse 5.
Colossians
2 and
5. For though I be absent in the flesh,
yet am I with you in the
spirit, joining and beholding your order
and the steadfastness of your faith in
Christ.
So now if you can't get there physically
and you're there watching, then you're
with us in the spirit. But we can't call
it the uh uh holy convocation that God
spoke of in Leviticus the 23rd chapter.
That's physical. But if you can't do the
physical and you do it spiritually,
you're still doing
well. Continue. That's all I have to
say. All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Moving on. Tracy Smith says, "How do I
talk to the people that is living wrong
and lead them back to God, the Lord, and
to read the Bible,
right? Sound like they got some
compassion for some people here."
Brother Dre, what you say?
Let's go to uh Titus the second chapter.
Titus 2 and we're gonna read verse one
and skip. Titus
2 verse one and then we'll skip. Go
ahead, brother Tanzel. But speak thou
the things which become sound doctrine.
So if you going to speak to somebody,
you speak the things that become sound
doctrine, which is the word of God.
Verse seven, go ahead.
and all things showing thyself a pattern
of good works and doctrine showing
unccorruptness, gravity, sincerity.
Go ahead. Sound speech that cannot be
condemned, that he that is of the
contrary part may be ashamed, having no
evil thing to say of you.
So if you speaking the word of God and
you are living the word of God, then
that sound speech that you going to
bring forth may prick their
hearts and cause them to take heed to
what it is you saying. Now let's go over
to uh Proverbs
25 and verse read verse 11 and 12.
Proverbs 25 11 and
12. Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
A word fitly spoken is like apples of
gold and pitches of silver.
And an earring of gold and an ornament
of fine gold. So is a wise reprover upon
an obedient ear. So a word fitly spoken,
you you have to speak it when it's time
to. Sometimes it ain't time to speak a
word, right? You know, let's go over to
one more place. Let's go over to
Ecclesiastics 12. Ecclesiastics 12 and
pick it up at verse 9. Ecclesiastics 12
and 9. Go ahead. And moreover, because
the preacher was
wise, he still taught the people
knowledge, yet he gave good heed and
sought out and set in order many
proverbs. Go ahead. And the preacher
sought to find out acceptable words. And
that which was written was upright, even
words of truth. So you seek out of the
word of God to find out acceptable
words, even words of truth. And
sometimes them words may not feel good,
but they are the right thing for our
healing and for us to be reproved enough
to change our ways. Verse 11. Go ahead.
The words of the wise are as gold and as
nails fastened by the masters of
assemblies
which are given from one shepherd.
That's right. That one shepherd is the
Lord and it is his word. And sometimes
that word as a goal will prick you and
hurt you. But at the end of the day it
will heal you even into everlasting life
if we do what we are called to do.
Read verses 13 and 14 and that's it. Go
ahead. Well, let us hear the conclusion
of the whole matter. Fear God and keep
his commandments. For this is the whole
duty of man. For God shall bring every
work into judgment with every secret
thing, whether it be good or whether it
be evil. You know, in in Proverbs 18 and
19, it says, "A brother
offended is harder to be one than a
strong
city." And his contentions are like
that, like the bars of a castle.
So if we choose our words, which is the
word of God, and we speak that word in
season, it will have an effect. lay it
on the table, but make
sure look to season those words that
that it may uh prick the the hearers.
That's all I got.
All right, thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next one. Moving on.
Randy Sims says, "Before the coming of
the Lord, before he takes Israel back to
the land, Malachi 4:E5 must happen first
before the Lord comes." Am I right?
All right. Are they right, brother
Jerome? Let's go read it. Um Malachi 4
and5. You get it? Go ahead and read.
Behold, I will send you Elijah the
prophet before the coming of the great
and dreadful day of the Lord.
Okay, so this is a prophecy that
actually it's already taking place
already. Okay. Um and it's kind of going
on even in these modern days, you know,
uh because this this spirit is simply
the word of God. That's really what it
is, okay? And he give it to his uh
servants,
namely uh the children of Israel,
namely, okay? So that it can be spread
out into all of the world. Okay? Call it
the spirit of Elijah here, but it's it's
really the word of God. But let's go to
um Luke. All right? Because it talked
about
uh John the Baptist coming in the spirit
of
Elijah. Okay. So, let's go to Luke the
first
chapter and we going to pick it up uh at
verse 11. Read it to the 13. We going to
skip when you get it. Go ahead. And
there appeared unto him an angel of the
Lord standing on the right side of the
altar of incense. And when Zachariah saw
him, he was troubled, and fear fell upon
him. And the angel said unto him, "Fear
not, Zacharias, for thy prayer is heard,
and thy wife Elizabeth shall bear thee a
son, and thou shalt call his name John."
Skip down and read verse 16 and 17.
And many of the children of Israel shall
he turn to the Lord their God. He shall
go before him in the spirit and power of
Elias, to turn the hearts of the father
to the children of the the
disobedience to the wisdom of the just
to make ready a people prepared for the
Lord. See, when this spirit of Elijah
went forth, he said it was John the
Baptist came in that spirit and all the
servants of the Lord that he gave this
this word to, they coming in that same
spirit for the purpose of getting people
ready for the coming of the Lord that he
got to give them that that truth. All
right, that's the spirit of Elijah. So,
uh it's going on already.
be long before the Lord come. You know
that's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
We move on to our next question with a
time check. Yes, the time is
8:25.
Marsita
says, "In your last lesson, unto Judah
shall the gathering of the people be.
You said Shiloh is one of Jesus' names."
Genesis 49 verse 10. I couldn't see it
in Joshua 18. It talks about silo as a
place. Where is it saying this is Jesus'
name?
All right. Looks like this starts off in
Genesis 49 and10 and the guest caller
will take it from there.
Read it.
Genesis 49 and
10. The set shall not depart from Judah,
nor a lawgiver from between his feet
until Shiloh come. and unto him shall
the gathering of the people be. No. Now,
let's examine this. You know, sometime
people read and you looking at scripture
and you don't and you don't know what
you're looking at. We going to examine
this. It said the shcept shall not
depart from Judah until shallow come.
And that's what it said. Yep.
It said to
him shall the people be gathered
together. It didn't say to it. Isn't
that correct? To him.
Now the reason we know that uh uh and
now let's go to Jeremiah the 7th
chapter. See sometime if you read a
verse all of a sudden it take it
somewhere else. First thing is you got a
person that's called that's named
Shalom. Shalom because it said him till
the gathering of the people be. So now
let's go into Jeremiah the 7th chapter
and read verse 12.
But go ye now unto my place which was in
Shiloh where I set my name at the first
and see what I did to it for the
wickedness of my people Israel.
Listen now look at
Shiloh the place where I set my name at
the first.
Yeah. Shallow is a person. So this place
that shallow was where the Lord said he
said his name at. Did you finish that
verse? That verse. Yeah.
Okay. Well, let's go further. Let's go
into D. Let's see who go who who going
to gather the
people. Let's go to Deuteronomy the 30th
chapter. Read verses
1-4. Deuteronomy 30. And it shall come
to pass when all these things are come
upon thee, the blessing and the curse,
which I have set before thee, and thou
shalt call them to mind among all the
nations, whether the Lord thy God have
driven thee, and shall return unto the
Lord thy God, and shall obey his voice,
according to all that I command thee
this day, thou and thy children, with
all thine heart, and with all thy soul,
that then the Lord thy God will turn thy
captivity
and have compassion upon thee, and will
return and gather thee from all the
nations, whether the Lord thy God have
scattered thee, if any of thine be
driven out into the outmost parts of
heaven. From then will the Lord thy God
gather thee, and from thence will he
fetch thee.
So, who's doing the gathering? The Lord.
Isn't that correct? Right. That's right.
But what l But what Lord? Uh uh uh uh
uh. But then now let's go and see what
Lord that's talking about. Let's go into
the second Thessalonians the 2 chapter
and read verse
one second
Thessalonians 2 chapter.
Now we beseech you, brethren, by the
coming of our Lord Jesus Christ and by
our gathering together unto him. And by
our what? Our gathering together unto
him. Oh, so they going to be gathered to
Jesus. Isn't that correct? What?
According to what's written there.
That's right. Go Jeremiah 31 and read
verse 10.
Jeremiah 31 and
verse
10. Hear the word of the Lord, oh ye
nations, and declare it into the owls a
far off, and say, he that scatter Israel
will gather him and keep him as a
shepherd do with his flock.
Oh, so the one that scattered Israel is
the one that's going to gather them.
Isn't that correct? That's right.
And you know that one that tried to
gather a lot, but Israel would not.
Let's see who that is. Let's go into
Luke the 13th chapter and read verse
10. Luke 13 and 10. And he was teaching
in one of the synagogues on the
Sabbath. And behold, there were a woman
which had a a spirit of infirmities.
Wait a minute. This this 13-10.
You said Luke 13:10. That was Luke
13-10.
Well, maybe I'm starting wrong. It's I
think maybe I got where it said Jesus
said that uh
uh oh Jerusalem Jerusalem killed the
prophets at that 21 Luke 21. Let's see.
I thought for sure was in the 13th
chapter alone.
Matthew the 23rd chapter.
Matthew 23 and 37 directly.
What's it say?
Matthew 23 and what? 37. Oh Jerusalem,
Jerusalem, thou that klest the prophet
and stone them which are sent unto thee.
How often would I have gathered thy
children together, even as a hen
gathered her chickens under her wings,
and you would not?
So, who was talking there? Jesus. Jesus.
Can you back up and see if you can see
read that it was Jesus?
[Music]
That's the first verse. Verse one. Yeah.
Then spake Jesus to the multitudes and
to his disciples. That's my job, man.
Slow down. Hey, you know we family. You
know when you're family, you work
together.
Okay then. So, we know that that was
Jesus
talking, but I still won't look. I don't
know how how is it that I know I'm
getting old, but my mind ain't that bad.
Let me look at still here. Even though
the uh question is is already
answered. Let's see.
[Music]
There's
13 and uh
[Music]
uh okay, there were 13 and 34. I'm
sorry. I want you to I want you to uh
but this is Jesus talking here. I want
you to read that 34th verse. You Matthew
13.
Uh-huh. No. Luke 13 and34.
Luke 13. Okay.
Oh, okay. Jesus. Jesus was lamenting
over Jerusalem when he come up on it.
Yep.
Okay. Go ahead and read 34. Oh,
Jerusalem, Jerusalem, which kleth the
prophet, and stonth them that I sent
unto thee. How often will I have
gathered thy children together as a hen
do have gathered her brood under her
wings? Wait a minute.
Did you pay attention to what he said? I
often will who have gathered you? I
There you go. I have gathered you
together as a hen gather a chicks. Go
finish that.
Behold, your house is left unto you
desolate.
And verily I say unto you, ye shall not
see me until the time come when ye shall
say, "Blessed is he that cometh in the
name of the Lord."
Now Jesus is the one that says going to
uh uh uh Jesus is is the God of the Old
Testament. First Corinthian the 10th
chapter tell you it was Jesus that
brought him Israel across the Red Sea,
right?
and Jesus and in uh and uh uh
uh St. John
5 5 and I think it's 37. I think it's 5
and 37 or 5 and 31 where it say the
father
himself has sent me. You have never
heard his voice at any time a seen is
shaped right
through now. And it says here that Jesus
is the one that's going to gather the
people. Isn't that right? Paul said
now. And it tell you that and let you
know when it said in Genesis the 10th
chapter, it said the septual shall not
depart from Judah until the Shiloh
come and to him shall the gathering of
the people be. Now they going to be
gathered to a place called
Shiloh or to a person which the Bible
called him.
to him shall the gathering of the people
be. There you go. So
Shiloh is one of Jesus name. Yep.
Because he is the only one that's going
to gather you. Nobody else. The father
won't come in on the scene until Jesus
have ruled this earth for a thousand
years at the white throne judgment. Then
everybody and then he going to terminate
death.
And now once he's done that then he is
going to give up render the kingdom to
the father and the father going to come
down in New Jerusalem. So
shallow is one of Jesus' name. The Bible
tell you get wisdom and knowledge but
with all your getting get understanding.
And you can't call
him an it, which is a
place. And most places are named after
somebody.
Yep. Jerusalem. That come after
Judah. That's all I have to say. All
right. Shallow. Shallowing Jesus. One
and the same.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Sister Deborah, are we going
into new territory?
Yes, we are. We are now into tonight's
Q&A for Wednesday, May the 28th,
2025. Brother Anthony Horesy wants you
to shed some light on the meaning of
Mark
2:es 21- 23.
Let's go to Mark 2, pick it up at verse
21.
Mark 23 and the guest caller take it
from there.
No man also saw a piece of new clothes
on an old garment. Else the new piece
that fill up it it fill it up taketh
away from the old and the rent is made
worse. And no man put up new wine into
old bottles. Else the new wine do burst
the bottles and the wine is spilled and
the bottles will be mur murdered. But
new wine must be put into new bottles.
Now you know this he now now he he's
telling you about
tradition and then he's given these as
an example. You know it's just like uh
it's saying that it's long cuz cuz you
going have to you have to back up and
read a little bit before you get there.
Back up to verse 18 and read down to ver
read 18- 20.
And the disciples of John and of the
Pharisees used to fast. And they came
and said unto him, "Why do the disciples
of John and of the Pharisees fast, but
the disciples fast not?" And Jesus said
unto them, "Can the children of the
bride chamber fast while the bridegroom
is with them? As long as they have the
bridegroom with them, they cannot fast.
But the days will come.
Go ahead. But the days will come when
the bridegroom shall be taken away from
them and then shall they fast in those
days.
So all he's saying is as long as he is
with the disciples, there's no reason
for them to fast.
to do so would be as would be uh uh be
as uh uh uh as out of place as the
example he gave in verse 21 and 22.
That's all he's saying. He said, "Look,
long as I'm here, they ain't got no
reason to fast."
And so it be just like uh uh putting a
new a patch a new patch on the old
government. You know why you fasting?
I'm here. Why are you grieving? I'm
here. Once I get taken away from you,
then I am then you have a reason to
fast.
So the whole thing is is that uh uh
uh when he
leave then there will be another thing
we want to read one
other and let's read that verse 21 and
22 again.
And no man also sawth a piece of new
clothes on an old garment, else the new
piece that fillth it up taketh away from
the old, and the rent is made
worse. And no man put up new wine into
old bottles. Else the new wine do burst
the bottles, and the wine is spilled,
and the bottles will be mared, but new
wine must be put into new bottles.
Now, now all it's really saying is that
look, just like you, you shouldn't fast
when your master is among you. You
shouldn't put the uh new uh patch on the
old garments, uh wine in a new bottle
cuz the wine go from it and it might
break the bottle. He said that's just as
that's out of place. That's all to it.
So why should they fast and and and uh
uh uh uh and suffer? Fast for what? The
Lord was walking with them, right?
So all So the new bottle of the new, you
know, wine in the patch is just a
metaphor. So just like you wouldn't
mourn while I'm here, uh just like uh
you wouldn't put new wine in the old
bottle or put a old patch on a a brand
new garment and uh uh uh cause damage.
You don't fast until your masters leave.
And once he leave, then we got we got
many reason to fast. Best of the way he
was taken away cuz he was killed on the
cross.
That's all it's talking
about. I hope it answers your question.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question. Next question. Audrey B
says, "If when you get baptized, all
your sins are forgiven, what are you
being judged for on judgment day?"
All right, Julius, if you get baptized
and all your sins are forgiven, what are
you being judged for on judgment day?
Let's see what the book say about that.
If all your sins are forgiven, let's go
to Acts the second chapter.
cuz you going to be judged by the things
that we done in this life by your
works. Baptism does not make you
sinfree, right?
Acts two and let's go and let's look
what the chief apostle said. Acts 2,
Tanzel, we going to read verse 36 to 38.
When you get it, go ahead. Therefore,
let all the house of Israel know
assuredly that God hath made the same
that same Jesus whom he had crucified
both Lord and Christ. Go. Now, these are
the people that had something to do with
the crucifixion of Jesus, all the
setting up that happened to him. Go
ahead.
Now, when they heard this, they were
pricricked in their hearts and said unto
and to the rest of the apostles, men and
brethren, what should we do? We've done
wrong and they sorry. What shall we do?
Look what Peter said. Go ahead. Then
Peter said unto them, repent and be
baptized every one of you in the name of
Jesus Christ for the remission of sins.
For the remission for the forgiveness of
sins. Go ahead. And you shall receive
the gift of the Holy Ghost. Now, how
long does this remission of sins? Let's
go and let's look at what Paul said in
Romans the third chapter.
Bend your Bibles to Romans the 3rd
chapter and we going to start this at at
verse 23. We're going to read 23 to 25.
Tenzel, when you get it, Romans
3:23, for all what? For all have sinned
and come short of the glory of God. Go
ahead. Being justified freely by his
grace through the redemption that is in
Christ Jesus. How did he redeem us? By
dying on the cross in our place. But for
how long? Go ahead. For God has set
forth to be a propitiation through faith
in his blood to declare his
righteousness for the remission of sins
that are passed. No. For your sins.
Period. That are passed. Oh, for that
are passed. When you get baptized, you
in the name of Jesus, you are forgiven
of your sins that are passed. Go ahead.
Right. Through the forbearance of God.
Okay. To show you for your sins that are
passed, but you still flesh and blood.
So now let's go to Hebrews the 10th
chapter. Hebrews chapter
10. Because you get baptized don't make
you sin free. You are still flesh and
blood. That's why when we baptize people
in of God, we always say in prayer, if
they should fall, then give them the
mind to get back up again.
Hebrews 10:26. Read it, bro. But if we
sin willfully after that, we have
received the knowledge of the truth. You
receive the knowledge of the truth. You
got you repented. You got baptized in
the name of Jesus for sins that are
passed. But if you sin
willfully, you know better and you don't
care about it. After you receive the
knowledge of the truth, go ahead. There
remain of no more sacrifice for sins.
Christ ain't going to die for you no
more. Go ahead. But a certain fearful
looking for judgment and fiery
indignation which shall devour the
adversaries. That's why Jesus say
repent and don't let sin be your ruin.
Right? So you are forgiven. You get
baptized. That's not that does not clear
you for sin
forever. No, no, no, no. Because you
flesh and blood, you going to fall maybe
inadvertently, but you still can sin. So
if you sin willfully after you known the
truth and you don't repent, you going to
die in your sins and ain't no more
sacrifices. Ain't no more animal
sacrifices that done away. And Jesus
done came and shed his blood. That done
away. You done walked up under the blood
of Jesus. You only have the lake of fire
to look forward to. That's right. And
you're going to be judged by the things
that are written in this book. So
therefore, don't sin
willfully. Baptism only push you up
under the covenant, but it don't make
you sin free. That's all I got. Anybody
want to add to that? It is a fearful
thing to fall into the hands of the
living God. That's book right there.
If you happen to fall, brother, get up
and get back in that race and keep
running and ask for forgiveness. That's
why you have to ask for forgiveness.
[Music]
That sound like the Lord said the Lord
said seven Ecclesiastes. I think it's
around the 12th
chapter and we read it every Sabbath
day.
Yes, sir.
And 13 and 14.
Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of
man. For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil. So now once you've been washed of
your
sin, then you have to keep the
commandments.
And if you don't make the first
resurrection, you going to find yourself
in judgment
day and you going to be judged according
to what's written in this book. And the
main thing that Jesus told the young man
that asked him what should he do to get
saved? He said keep the commandments. So
now Christ said, let us hear the
conclusion of the whole matter. Fear God
and keep his
commandments. That's the whole duty of
man. But God shall bring every work in
the judgment with everything whether it
be good or whether it be evil. Until you
are changed into the God's family,
you're not saved. So that mean you got
to keep these
commandments or you're going to be
judged. That's all I have to say. All
right, we're going to move on to our
next question. Sister Deborah's time is
ticking. Yes, Benjamin Taylor had had a
response in a question to Little Mama
Hayes question last week that asks, "The
new Poke Leo is from the Augustine order
lineage, which has something to do with
the transatlantis slave trade. Is it
true that Rome had a part in the
transatlantis slave trade?" Now he says
it is
incorrect in saying that the Catholic
Church did not play a role in the
Atlantis slave trade. Uh to the
contrary, the Catholic Church role in
the transatlantic slave trade was a
complex one. both Catholics and
Protestants supported slavery and
benefit from the
institution.
So with that uh response in
question,
brother Okay. So um brother Julius um
lay out a little more light on that
question. I answered the question and uh
I stand by my answer although I
understand what he's saying because the
response that Benjamin Taylor got is he
got it off of
Wikipedia. I read the same stuff and I
said indirectly no they didn't but
indirectly they
did. All nations had a part in the slave
trade. Our first slave sellers was
Hamite. We was in Egypt and then the uh
they sold Joseph, his own brothers sold
him to uh to the Hamites and the
Hammites sold him to the
IshRaelites. Let me show you something.
What I didn't tell you last week was
what and I apologize for that. What I
want to show you is who is behind the
transatlantic slave trade. Let's go to
Deuteronomy 28th chapter.
See, everybody want to point fingers,
but we need to actually understand how
we got ourselves into this, right?
Deuteronomy and why. And I'm not
justifying anything. I'm just saying we
need to look at matters of fact. Don't
nothing happen unless the Lord allow it
or permit it. Deuteronomy 28th chapter
and I want to pick this up at verse six
uh 15.
Tenzia, when you get it, go ahead,
brother. But it shall come to pass, if
thou will not hearken unto the voice of
the Lord thy God, to observe to do all
his commandments, and his statutes,
which I command thee this day, Uhhuh.
all these curses shall come upon thee,
and overtake thee. They're going to come
upon you. The first 14 verses is the
blessings of obedience, and the rest of
them 15 to 68 is the curses of
disobedience upon
Israel. Verse 16 quick.
Cursed shalt thou be in the city, and
cursed shalt thou be in the field. So
now, cursed shall you be in the city,
and cursed shall you be in the field.
Verse 32, read it.
Thy sons and thy daughters shall be
given unto another people, and thy eyes
shall look and fail with longing for
them all the day long, and there shall
be no might in thy hand, because you are
a captive. You are a captive. Verse 41.
41. Read it. Thou shalt begot sons and
daughters, but thou shalt not enjoy
them, for they shall go into captivity.
You going to go into captivity. That
means you are a captive. You're a slave.
Verse 68.
And the Lord shall bring thee into Egypt
again with ships. Now, we ain't going.
The Lord already told us we ain't going
back into Egypt anymore. Egypt to us
represents bondage, slavery. And the
Lord shall bring you into Egypt again.
This is metaphoric for slavery. Go
ahead. By the way whereof I spake unto
thee, thou shalt see it no more again,
and there ye shall be sold unto your
enemies for bond men and bond women, and
no man shall buy you. Bond men and bond
women. So, uh, the transatlantic slave
trade and all the slaveries before that
was bought on by the hand of God. So, it
wasn't just the captive church.
Everybody had a hand in in the slave in
in the slavery from our disobedience to
taking us out of the land all the way up
to the scattering of us in all the
nation. We didn't migrate here. We were
brought over here. Now, uh, you got the
the main players, Portugal, Spain,
France, and Great Britain. They were
huge, but they were all Catholic uh uh
uh Catholics. Even Protestants is a
derivative of the Catholic system. So
therefore, this is why I I regret that I
didn't answer that fully. So I hope this
helped with that right there. Let's not
point the finger at nobody. We did this
to us for our disobedience. That's all I
got. And we going to be in this
captivity until the times of the
Gentiles be fulfilled.
And then as we read earlier, then like
the guest caller said, then the Lord
going to send and gather us from all the
nations that he has scattered us. That's
all I got, Cordell.
Right. Yes, sir. Four corners put a lot
of hands into the the pie, didn't it,
Julius? The book said we going to be
hated by all nations. That's what he
said. All right. Not just Rome. Yeah.
So, so the Catholic Church and everybody
else had a hand in slavery.
Yes, sir.
All right. Hope that answered your
question there, Sister Deborah. We're
going to go to our next question. Yes.
Navy doc says a question uh Navy doc
says a question about age limit for the
Levites in numbers 4 there are numerous
scriptures that say from 50 excuse me
from 30 years to 50 years. However in
numbers 9 verse 25 and 26 it says the
age limit is from 25 years to 50. Is
this 25 years of age a typo?
Jerome, share some light.
Uh, no, it's not a typo, but let's go
read the verse that that you gave. Um,
Leviticus 9, was it 25 and
Numbers 9 25 and 26. Let's go read.
Let's go read that.
You said number N numbers nine. Yes.
Verses 25 and 26. Yeah. It's there is no
numbers 97.
Well, but I'm thinking you really mean
Numbers 8. Numbers 8 verse
25 and 26. Read that.
uh and from the age of 50 years they
shall cease waiting upon the service
thereof and shall serve no more but
shall minister with their brethren in
the tabernacle of the congregation to
keep the charge and shall do no service
thus shalt thou do unto the Levites
touching their charge.
Okay. Um did we read that 24 Jerome?
Yeah. In the question they had 25 but
yeah we g we going to read that. uh 24
because it establishes the
25. So read that verse
24. This is it that belongth unto the
Levites from 20 and 5 years old and
upward. They shall go into a wait unto
the service of the tabernacle of the
congregation. Okay. So now it's not a
typo as far as the age limit. What is
what is happening is that the they start
to wait to go into the uh ministry uh in
the tabernacle and they they starting
they waiting to do that work or that
service in the tabernacle from 25 years
and they don't get selected
uh to do the actual work and service in
the tabernacle. got up until
50 to be selected, but they can start at
30 because they can wait. They waiting
at 25, but they can they can start at
30, not before. They going to start at
30, but if they don't get selected, they
got all the way until 50 to be selected.
Now, let's just say they don't get
selected within that frame
of
25 to 50. Okay? Because they got from 30
years old to 50 to actually do the
service. All right? Uh then that's when
that
verse
20 come into play if they don't get
selected. So read that verse 26 again.
But shall minister with their brethren
in the tabernacle of the congregation to
keep the charge and shall do no service.
They but they don't they don't do no
service though cuz they didn't get it
selected in that time frame right which
is actually from 30 to 50 but they
starting their way that 25 okay uh but
they going they going to assist their
brother but they can't actually do no
service if they don't get selected in
that frame that time frame. Okay. So
that's all I got on it.
Right. All right, brother. Um, Cornell,
may we do one more uh question? You can.
Yes. Uh, Anthony Thomas asks,
"Will the son's kingdom and the father's
kingdom exist at the same
time?" And they want some scriptures.
where the son's kingdom and the father's
kingdom exist at the same time, not on
earth. Open to the panel.
Going to first Corinthians the 15th
chapter. Yes, sir.
I think we're going to start around
verse 21.
Okay, we going and we going we going to
read down
uh uh we just keep reading from 21. We
going to go and uh to 23 and then we
going to go right into 24.
Okay, read it. For since by man came
death, by man came also the resurrection
of the dead. For as in Adam all die, and
even so in Christ shall all be made
alive. But every man in his own order,
Christ the first fruits, afterward they
that are Christ at his coming.
Okay, go ahead. Now then cometh the end,
when he shall have the
then cometh the
end. Okay, start it back.
Then cometh the end, when he shall have
delivered up the kingdom to God, even
the father, when he shall have put down
all rule and all authority and power,
but he must reign till he have put all
enemies under his feet. And the last
enemy that shall be destroyed is death.
Now skip down to verse 28 and read it.
And when all things shall be subdued
unto him, then shall the son also
himself be subject unto him that put all
things unto him, that God may be all in
all.
Okay? So Jesus going is the one this
kingdom. He's going to run this earth
and he going to get everything in order
and he going to terminate death and then
he going to turn it over to the father.
Read that 24th verse one more
time. Then cometh the end when he shall
have delivered up the kingdom to God,
even the father, when he shall have put
down all rule and all authority and
power.
So no, long as we got flesh and blood
men, Jesus the only one that's going
going to have the kingdom and New
Jerusalem, the kingdom in heaven is then
the Lord going to bring that down later.
That's in Revelation the 21st chapter,
right? That's after everything is done.
There's no more judgment to be done.
There's no more
death. So everything is taken care of by
Jesus. Then he going to turn over to the
father. So, no, they're not ruling
simultaneously. That's all I have to
say.
Right, Sister Deborah? Time check. Yes,
the time is 9:03.
All right, 9:03. We have ran out of time
and we'd like to thank everybody from
all around the world who joined us. And
we'd like to say if you submitted a
question and we never have a chance to
get to it, please don't resubmit it.
Sister Deborah, take your question, put
it in rotation, and we will answer your
question next week. So once again, thank
you. And until we all come together
again, be safe, be blessed, stay prayed
up, and may the Lord have mercy on us
all as brother Tanzel closes us out. Our
Father, which are in heaven, hallowed be
thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread. And forgive
us of our debts as we forgive our debt
towards. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever.